Inventory of the World Without War Council records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Religious institutions, WWWC programs, 1965-1976 (Box 90)
- Turn Toward Peace, programs, conference materials, introductory materials, 1961-1967 (Box 91)
- WWWC programs (Box 91)
  - American Initiatives Project, 1962 (Box 91)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy, 1964 (Box 91)
  - Diablo Valley Education Project, 1968 (Box 91)
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War, 1965 (Box 91)
- Leaflets and brochures, 1974, undated (Box 91)
- International NGO Conference on Disarmament, 1978 (Box 91)
- Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 92-93)
  - Lowell Livezey and Robert Pickus, photocopies, 1973-1975 (Box 92)
  - Sandy Allport, 1975 (Box 93)
- Foundations and organizations (Box 93)
  - Apple Computer, 1988 (Box 93)
  - Asia Foundation, 1994 (Box 93)
  - BankAmerica Foundation, 1982 (Box 93)
  - CFS Foundation, 1982 (Box 93)
  - Compton Foundation, 1995 (Box 93)
  - Coro Foundation, 1988 (Box 93)
  - California Council for the Humanities, 1987 (Box 93)
  - Columbia Foundation, 1996 (Box 93)
  - East Bay Community Foundation, 1991 (Box 93)
  - Gerbode Foundation, 1988 (Box 93)
  - Goldman Fund, 1993 (Box 93)
  - Greenville Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 93)
  - Haigh-Scaten Foundation, 1997 (Box 93)
  - Handcock Foundation, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Heller Foundation, 1970-1990 (Box 93)
  - Helms Foundation, 1993 (Box 93)
  - Irving Foundation (Box 93)
  - Hume Foundation, 1994 (Box 93)
  - Walter Johnson Foundation (Box 93)
  - Jewish Fund for Justice (Box 93)
  - Koret Foundation (Box 93)
- Turn Toward Peace, correspondence, meeting materials, and policy framework, 1962-1964 (Box 94)
- World Community Associates, 1962 (Box 94)
- National Research Council on Peace Strategy, 1962 (Box 94)
- Alternatives to Disaster Conference, Kansas Institute of International Relations, 1962 (Box 95)
- Vietnam Day speech, Robert Pickus, 1965 (Box 95)
- Turn Toward Peace, promotional materials, 1961-1967 (Box 95)
- Diagrams, "Circle of Response" and "Functioning Peace Center" (Box 95)
- Correspondence, Robert Pickus, 1962-1965 (Box 95)
- Printed matter, 1984-1993 (Box 96)
- Operations Crossroads, Africa, 1988 (Box 96)
- New York Open Center, 1988 (Box 96)
- National Endowment for Democracy, newsletter and kit, 1986-1988 (Box 96)
- Religious organizations with WWWC programs, 1967-1975 (Box 97)
- Staff meetings, New York office, 1992-1993 (Box 97)
- Conferences, 1993 (Box 97)
- Correspondence, Robert Pickus, 1993 (Box 97)
- Alphabetical file (Box 98)
  Includes leaflets and brochures
  - Hunger Project, 1994 (Box 98)
  - Independent Scholars of Asia (Box 98)
  - Independent Socialist Club (Box 98)
  - Indochina Mobile Education Project (Box 98)
  - Institute for Democracy in South Africa, 1996 (Box 98)
  - Interfaith Witness for Peace in the Middle East (Box 98)
  - International Association of Educators for World Peace (Box 98)
  - International Commission of Jurists (Box 98)
  - Illinois Humanities Guidelines (Box 98)
  - Independent Initiatives, Soviet-American travel (Box 98)
  - Indochina Archive, University of California, Berkeley (Box 98)
  - Infact, Boston (Box 98)
  - North American Coordinating Committee, Palestine (Box 98)
  - National Association of Scholars (Box 98)
  - National Central American Health Rights Network (Box 98)
  - National Campaign for a Peace Tax Fund (Box 98)
  - National Council on U.S. Arab Relations (Box 98)
- Conference, "Ethical Dimensions of International Education,", 1988 (Box 98)
- Oregon Educational TV program, Robert Pickus, 1967 (Box 99)
- Diablo Valley School Project, prospectus, 1967-1970 (Box 99)
- "Acts for Peace: An Experimental Approach to Continuing Peace Education in Northern California," Lewis Hillyard (Box 99)
- "What Kind of Opposition to Militarism Makes Sense?" WWWC Midwest office, 1979 (Box 99)
- Correspondence, Robert Pickus, John Dixon, Max Kampelman, 1976-1977 (Box 100)
- WWWC programs (Box 100)
  - Peace and the Elections, 1972 (Box 100)
  - International Conflict and American Organizations Project (Box 100)
- WWWC Seattle, two year development program, 1977 (Box 100)
- Meeting materials, 1975 (Box 100)
- Notes on structure, purpose, and programs of WWWC, 1967-1968 (Box 101)
- "Assumptions of a World Without War Approach," Robert Pickus (Box 101)
- Meeting materials, 1972 (Box 101)
- Pickus office files, 1970-1973 (Box 101)
- Biographical information, Robert Pickus (Box 102)
- Report on work in Washington, George Weigel, 1982-1983 (Box 102)
- Preface to Neither Victims nor Executioners (Box 102)
- Job descriptions and interview questions (Box 102)
- Printed matter, 1975-1977 (Box 102)
- "U.S. Policy Choices in Vietnam and Our Response," Robert Pickus (Box 103)
- Turn Toward Peace, executive committee (Box 103)
- Nuclear weapons protests, 1957-1958 (Box 103)
- Printed matter, circa 1960-1969 (Box 103)
- WWWC programs (Box 104)
  - American Initiatives Project, 1981-1982 (Box 104)
  - Peace and Elections, 1972 (Box 104)
- Turn Toward Peace, 1961 (Box 104)
- WWWC start up materials, 1966-1974 (Box 105)
  Includes correspondence, meeting minutes, intern program materials, and financial records related to the establishment of the organization
- Printed matter related to economics, 1976-1978 (Box 106)
- WWWC Midwest, "World Economic Development as a Range of Views" (Box 106)
- Acts for Peace and Turn Toward Peace, correspondence and printed matter, 1959-1962 (Box 107)
- National Endowment for Democracy grants, 1992-1993 (Box 108)
- Foundations (Box 109)
  - Montgomery Street Foundation, 1993 (Box 109)
  - Plowshares Fund, 1996 (Box 109)
  - Rosenberg Foundation (Box 109)
  - San Francisco Foundation, 1995 (Box 109)
  - Schultz Foundation, 1995 (Box 109)
  - Southern California Association for Philanthropy (Box 109)
  - The Tides (Box 109)
  - Haas School of Business (Box 109)
  - The California Wellness Foundation (Box 109)
- Jewish organizations and culture, 1964 (Box 110)
- Scientific organizations, 1970-1971 (Box 111)
  Includes Scientists and Engineers for Social and Political Action
- Religious organizations, 1971-1975 (Box 111)
- Foundations (Box 112)
  - Henry Jackson Foundation (Box 112)
  - The Heritage Foundation (Box 112)
  - The Hesperian Foundation (Box 112)
  - The Holy Land Fellowship of Christians and Jews (Box 112)
  - The Hoover Institution (Box 112)
  - The Hudson Institute (Box 112)
  - Henry George School of Social Change (Box 112)
  - Humanities, International Human Rights (Box 112)
  - The Hunger Project (Box 112)
- Strategies of peace (Box 113)
  - "After Containment, A Strategy of Peace," Robert Woito, 1992 (Box 112)
  - "Nonviolence Speaks to Power," Petra Kelly, 1992 (Box 112)
  - WWWC Midwest, "A Strategy of Peace," Rafael Brinner, 1992 (Box 112)
  - "Changing Our Ways," Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 112)
- "Thinking About War and Peace in America: A Failure Examined," Robert Pickus (Box 114)
- WWWC Seattle, by-laws (Box 114)
- Regional Executive Committee, meeting materials, 1966 (Box 114)
- Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 114)
- WWWC Midwest, program report (Box 114)
- Report From Leningrad, Holt Ruffin, 1990 (Box 114)
- Printed matter, 1971-1982 (Box 115)
- "World Peace Needs Ideas," poster, 1980 (Box 115)
- Foreign policy perspectives of different organizations (Box 115)
- Gene Sharp file (Box 116)
- Program on Nonviolent Sanctions, Doug Bond (Box 116)
- Organizations (Box 116-117)
  - AFL-CIO (Box 116)
  - American Enterprise Institute (Box 116)
  - American Forum for Global Education (Box 116)
  - American Committee on Africa (Box 116)
  - Overseas Development Council (Box 117)
  - Overseas Development Network (Box 117)
  - Oxfam Network (Box 117)
  - Oxfam America (Box 117)
  - A2S2, Policy Street: The Think Tank View (Box 117)
  - Central American Resource Center (Box 117)
  - Pacific American Institute (Box 117)
  - Pacific Neighbor News (Box 117)
  - Pacific Institute (Box 117)
  - Planetary Citizens (Box 117)
  - Presbyterian Church, Commitment to Peacemaking (Box 117)
- Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 48th General Assembly, 1965 (Box 118)
- FOR and Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1965-1967 (Box 118)
- Judaism and War kit (Box 118)
- Foundations (Box 119-120)
  - Exxon Educational Foundation, 1979 (Box 119)
  - Faigel Leah Foundation, 1975 (Box 119)
  - Field Foundation, 1975 (Box 119)
  - Fund for Peace, 1971 (Box 119)
  - Film Fund (Box 119)
  - Ford Foundation, 1996 (Box 119)
  - Laucks Foundation, circa 1967-1997 (Box 120)
  - Levi-Strauss Foundation (Box 120)
- Correspondence, Elizabeth Mandel (Box 120)
- Glasnost issues, 1987-1990 (Box 121)
  Samizdat journal edited by Sergei Grigoryants
- Smith Richardson Foundation, corresopndence and grant request, 1983-1992 (Box 122)
- "Contexts and Issues: Two Approaches," Robert Pickus (Box 123)
- Conference, Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War, 1965 (Box 123)
- Office file, 1968-1969 (Box 123)
- Negotiations Now (Box 123)
- "Working for a World Without War," study kit (Box 124)
  For use with Oregon Education Television program featuring Robert Pickus, 1967
- Union of American Hebrew Congregations, correspondence, conference materials, brochures, seminar kit, 1966-1970 (Box 125)
- "Personal and Philosophical Statement," Noah Pickus (Box 126)
- "Getting Started on Our Study of NGOs and International Human Rights," Lowell Livezey, 1980 (Box 126)
- Conferences, 1979-1985 (Box 126)
- Office files, correspondence, reports, meeting materials, 1974-1980 (Box 127)
- National Council on Philanthropy program, 1977 (Box 127)
- National Federation of Priests Council program, 1975 (Box 127)
- International Conflict and American Organizations project, circa 1970-1979 (Box 127)
- California Council for the Humanities, Governance in World Politics, 1997 (Box 128)
- Common Good/Immigrants and Citizenship Program (Box 128)
- Foundations (Box 129-131)
  - Robert McCormick Charitable Trust, Military Museum (Box 129)
  - Joyce Mertz-Gilmore Foundation, 1980-1996 (Box 129)
  - New Land Foundation, 1978 (Box 130)
  - New World Foundation (Box 130)
  - New York Community Trust (Box 130)
  - New York Humanities Council (Box 130)
  - New York Friends Group (Box 130)
  - New York State Council for the Arts (Box 130)
  - Normadie Foundation (Box 130)
  - Norman Foundation, 1982 (Box 130)
  - Olin Foundation (Box 130)
  - Pew Charitable Trusts (Box 130)
  - Glenmede Trust, NAE (Box 130)
  - Harry Frank Guggenheim Foundation, 1984 (Box 131)
  - Gund Foundation, 1984 (Box 131)
  - Charles Evans Hughes Memorial Fund (Box 131)
  - Institute for Educational Affairs (Box 131)
  - International Telegraph and Educational Aid (Box 131)
  - Henry Jackson Foundation (Box 131)
  - J.M. Foundation, 1989 (Box 131)
  - Japan Foundation (Box 131)
  - J.M. Kaplan Fund (Box 131)
  - List Foundation (Box 131)
  - MacArthur Foundation (Box 131)
  - MaGowan Family Foundation (Box 131)
  - Mayer Family Foundation (Box 131)
- WWWC programs (Box 132)
  - Television Project, 1971 (Box 132)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy: An Overview, 1976 (Box 132)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 133)
- Harry Guggenheim Foundation, 1972-1974, undated (Box 133)
- Society for Citizen Education in the World, 1970 (Box 133)
- Science file, 1970 (Box 133)
- Correspondence (Box 134)
  - Wasserman, Hannah and Felix, 1970-1985 (Box 134)
  - Winton, Mike and Penny (Box 134)
  - Ferry, Ping (Box 134)
  - Ewing, Linda (Box 134)
  - Jacob Blaustein Institute (Box 134)
  - Aquinas Fund (Box 134)
  - Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation (Box 134)
  - Bayard Rustin Fund (Box 134)
  - The Bedminister Fund (Box 134)
  - Boehm Fund (Box 134)
  - Booth Ferris Foundation (Box 134)
  - Buffett Foundation (Box 134)
- George Weigel, speeches and writings, 1979-1989 (Box 135)
- Conferences and workshops (Box 136)
  - Peacekeeping in the Nuclear Age: A Workshop for Educators, 1990 (Box 136)
  - “Improving History and Civic Education,” National Center for History in the Schools, U.S. Department of Education, 1991 (Box 136)
  - "Education for Democracy has America Talking," American Federation of Teachers (Box 136)
  - Building Quality International Education Programs through University/School Collaboration, 1992 (Box 136)
- Photocopies of materials from chronological and program files, 1971-1975 (Box 137)
- Conscientious objectors, 1943-1956 (Box 138-139)
  Includes material related to the Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors
- "An Introduction to the Ideas in To End War and Future of Publications" (Box 139)
- Correspondence, Tim Zimmer, Robert Pickus, 1974 (Box 139)
- Improving American Competence in World Affairs (Box 140)
- Office files, board meeting materials, reports, and correspondence, 1970-1994 (Box 140)
- Organizations (Box 141-142)
  - American Youth Hostels (Box 141)
  - Americans for Democracy in Russia (Box 141)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding (Box 141)
  - Aurora Foundation (Box 141)
  - The Atlantic Council of the United States (Box 141)
  - Association to Unite the Democracies (Box 141)
  - Association of Arab American University Graduates (Box 141)
  - Amnesty discussion papers (Box 141)
  - Applied Communication Technology (Box 141)
  - The Fielding Institute (Box 141)
  - Flagship Earth (Box 141)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 141)
  - Forum for World Affairs (Box 141)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 141)
  - Forum on Community and the Environment, 1984 (Box 141)
  - Foundation for Global Community (Box 141)
  - Foundation for Social Innovators (Box 141)
  - Fourth Freedom Forum (Freedom from Fear of War) (Box 141)
  - Free Trade Union Institute (Box 141)
  - Freedom from Hunger Institute (Box 141)
  - Freedom House (Box 141)
  - Freedom Monitor (Box 141)
  - National Council of Churches (Box 142)
  - National Council of World Affairs Organizations (Box 142)
  - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs (Box 142)
  - National Endowment for Democracy (Box 142)
  - National Gun Control Council (Box 142)
  - National Institute for Public Policy (Box 142)
  - National Inter-Religious Service Board for Conscientious Objectors (Box 142)
  - National Organization of Women (Box 142)
  - National Peace Garden (Box 142)
  - Alliance for Our Common Future (Box 142)
  - National Republican Institute for International Affairs (Box 142)
  - National Urban League (Box 142)
  - Northern California War Tax Refusers (Box 142)
  - Hiroshima Panorama Project (Box 142)
  - New Atlantic Initiative (Box 142)
- WWWC programs
  - U.S. Response to the Arms Race, 1983 (Box 143)
  - American Initiatives Project, 1981 (Box 143)
- Speeches and writings (Box 143)
  - George Weigel, 1981-1982 (Box 143)
  - Robert Pickus, 1982-1991 (Box 143)
  - Others, 1982-1988 (Box 143)
- American Initiatives Project, 1980-1982 (Box 144)
- "Steady Work," WWWC reports, 1980-1993 (Box 145)
- "Peace Betrayed," preface, Robert Pickus, 1989 (Box 145)
- WWWC programs (Box 145)
  - Alliance for Education in Global and International Studies (AEGIS) (Box 145)
  - Strategy of Peace statements (Box 145)
  - California Civil Rights Initiative, 1993 (Box 145)
- Turn Toward Peace, correspondence, meeting materials, and program materials, 1962-1965 (Box 146)
- Diocese of California, Episcopal, Program, 1971-1972 (Box 147)
- WWWC Seattle office, 1968-1987 (Box 148)
- Correspondence and program materials from Chicago, Seattle, and Berkeley offices, 1969-1973 (Box 149)
- Seattle office, newsletter, correspondence, reports, and publication file, 1989-1992 (Box 150)
- Center for Civil Society International, 1992-1996 (Box 150)
- Vietnam, printed matter (Box 151)
- WWWC programs (Box 152-154)
  - Diocese of California, Episcopal, Program, 1971-1974 (Box 152)
  - Conscience and War, 1969-1981 (Box 153)
  - National Council on Philanthropy, 1973-1977 (Box 154)
- Vietnam, printed matter (Box 155)
- Draft counselors, 1980-1983 (Box 156)
- WWWC programs
  - State Department/Independent Sector Project, 1974-1985 (Box 157)
  - National Council on Philanthropy, 1977-1979 (Box 158)
- National Association of Evangelicals, 1991-1992 (Box 159)
- "Developing the Course," Robert Pickus, 1989-1990 (Box 159)
- Acts for Peace and Turn Toward Peace, 1960-1965 (Box 160)
- National Council on Philanthropy, 1978-1979 (Box 161)
- "Report on Trip to Poland and Czechoslovakia," Holt Ruffin, 1988 (Box 162)
- Database of Independent Contacts in the Soviet Union (Box 162)
- USA/CIS Project, Connecting Civil Societies (Box 162)
- George Weigel, speeches and writings, 1978-1987 (Box 163)
- WWWC programs
  - State Department/Independent Sector Project (Box 164)
  - Bay Area Americans and World Affairs Fellows Program, 1981 (Box 164)
  - Improving American Competence in World Affairs, 1981 (Box 164)
  - International Conflict and American Organizations (ICAO), 1979 (Box 164)
- "The Council and the Strategic Defense Initiative,", 1985 (Box 164)
- "How an American Jew Came to Live and Work with South African Calvinists," Noah Pickus (Box 164)
- Printed matter, 1975-1979 (Box 165)
- "A Critique of the World Without War Council," Jay Lippman (Box 165)
- Correspondence (Box 165)
- Turn Toward Peace, "the first years,", 1962-1964 (Box 166)
- Printed matter, 1943-1955 (Box 167)
- American Friends Service Committee, 1951-1958 (Box 167)
- East Bay Draft Information and Counseling Center (EBDICC), 1968 (Box 168)
- Conscientious objectors and the draft (Box 168)
- Printed matter, 1961-1966 (Box 169)
- University of California extension course, "Working Effectively for a World Without War,", 1967 (Box 169)
- "The New Politics," Robert Pickus and Arthur Waskow (Box 169)
- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 170)
- SANE, leaflets and clippings, 1961 (Box 170)
- Strategic Arms Limitation Talks (SALT) (Box 170)
- New York office, board meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 171)
- Flyers, foreign policy speakers, circa 1980 (Box 171)
- International Human Rights Conference, 1979 (Box 171)
  Organized and sponsored by WWWC
- Vietnam and Cambodia, printed matter, 1950-1972 (Box 172)
- Religious organizations and the draft, 1981-1982 (Box 173)
- "Judaism and War," Robert Pickus (Box 173)
- Box Removed From Collection (Box 174-180)
- Program materials, 1960-1991 (Box 181-182)
- Study kit used for Oregon Education Television program, 1967 (Box 182)
- Brochures and publications from other organizations (Box 183)
- Project South Africa, 1984-1987 (Box 184)
  Intitiated in 1983 by Bayard Rustin, with the goal of linking NGOs in the United States with similar organizations in South Africa to strengthen civil society, enabling change to take place without violence.
- Berkeley office, newsletters, program material, SANE controversy (Box 185)
- East Bay Draft Information and Counseling Center (EBDICC), 1968-1974 (Box 186)
- Photocopies of program materials and financial records, 1965-1986 (Box 187)
- Funding files (Box 188)
- "Social Change, the Nonviolent Approach, and the Peace Effort" (Box 189)
- Organizations (Box 189)
  Includes National Endowment for Democracy
- Negotiations Now, 1967-1968 (Box 190)
- National Council on Philanthropy, 1975-1980 (Box 190)
- Voluntary Organizations Conference, 1965 (Box 190)
- American Initiatives Project (Box 190)
- National Federation of Priests Council, correspondence, program materials, convention reports, 1972-1976 (Box 191)
- New York Office files, 1969-1974 (Box 192)
- New York Office correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 193)
- Research files (Box 194)
  Includes files on United States and world politics, and a human resources conference in Copenhagen
- Project South Africa (Box 195)
- Northern California Consultative Group (Box 196)
- Non-governmental organizations, circa 1970-1975 (Box 197)
- U.S. Response to the Arms Race program, 1976-1978 (Box 198)
- UN Special Sessions on Disarmament, 1976-1978 (Box 198)
- Program files and leadership training (Box 199)
- Turn Toward Peace, Pacific regional office (Box 199)
- Turn Toward Peace, program files, 1961-1967 (Box 200-201)
  Includes Conscience and War program materials.
- Transition from Turn Toward Peace to World Without War Council, 1967-1975 (Box 201)
- Clippings, 1978-1985 (Box 202)
- Draft counseling materials (Box 202)
- Research files, "South Asia to the United Nations" (Box 203)
- American Friends Service Committee, Chicago office, 1952-1954 (Box 204)
- Board meetings, program files, and promotional materials, 1973-1976 (Box 205)
- WWWC programs (Box 206)
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War (Box 206)
  - U.S. Response to the Arms Race (Box 206)
  - General program files, 1975-1980 (Box 206)
- Twentieth Anniversary Program (Box 206)
- WWWC Issues Center, 1971 (Box 206)
- Board meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 207)
- Program goals, 1980-1981 (Box 207)
- Photographs of Robert Pickus (Box 207)
- Personnel and intern records, A-J, circa 1965-1995 (Box 208)
- WWWC programs (Box 208)
  - International Conflict and American Organizations, 1975-1981 (Box 209)
  - State Department/Independent Sector (Box 209)
  - East Bay Draft Information and Counseling Service, 1969-1972 (Box 210)
  - General program files, circa 1970-1979 (Box 210)
- Board meetings, 1972 (Box 210)
- Board meetings, New York Board of Directors, 1978-1990 (Box 211)
- "Development of the Peace Effort's Hard Core After World War II," Ted Olsen (Box 212)
- "Peace and the American Community: A Manual for Instructors in a Work and Study Program for Peace Internes," Ted Olsen (Box 212)
- Turn Toward Peace, correspondence, circa 1960-1969 (Box 212)
- Correspondence, New York Office (Box 213)
- WWWC Circulars and bulk mailing material, 1977-1989 (Box 214)
- Financial records, 1975-1977 (Box 215)
- Teaching Unites, global education, 1978-1981 (Box 217)
- Correspondence, Robert Pickus (Box 216)
- Chronolgical file, photocopies, 1992-1994 (Box 218)
- Personnel files, New York Office, 1975-1993 (Box 219)
  Arranged alphabetically by staff member or intern.
- Bulk materials, 1960-1976 (Box 220)
- Board and Executive Committee meetings, 1971-1978 (Box 221)
- Turn Toward Peace, photocopies, 1961-1967 (Box 222)
- Office files, New York Office, 1967-1974 (Box 222)
- National Council on Philanthropy, 1975-1980 (Box 223)
- Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE) (Box 224)
- Printed matter, circa 1990-1999 (Box 224)
- Research files on pacifism, arms control, disarmament (Box 225)
  Includes "The Grindstone Experiment, Thirty-One Hours," by Ted Olsen and Gorden Christiansen
- East Bay Draft Information and Counseling Service, circa 1965-1975 (Box 226)
- Financial records, 1994-1997 (Box 227)
- Printed matter, United Nations (Box 228)
- Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 229)
- Catholic World Education Center, 1973-1983 (Box 230)
- Intern program, correspondence, 1968 (Box 231)
- Grant application, California Council for the Humanities, 1976 (Box 231)
- WWWC programs (Box 231)
  - Assessing the Public Effort for Peace, 1983-1986 (Box 231)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy: An Overview, undated (Box 231)
- "Working for a World Without War," Robert Pickus, draft, undated (Box 231)
- San Jose Jewish Colloquim, guidelines for thinking about war and peace, undated (Box 231)
- Board and corporation meetings, 1968-1975 (Box 232)
- Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 233)
- Financial records, 1978-1988 (Box 234)
- Research file and program materials, 1978-1981 (Box 235)
  Includes articles on disarmament
- Research file (Box 236)
  Includes materials on sanctuary, pacifism, the Conscience and War program, and the Democracy Project
- National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE) (Box 237)
- Financial records, circa 1961-1973 (Box 238)
- Printed matter and non-governmental oragnizaions (Box 239)
  Includes "Catholic Social Teachings"
- Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 240)
- Office files, New York Office, 1975-1978 (Box 240)
- Improving American Competence in World Affairs program, 1980 (Box 240)
- National Federation of Priests Council, amnesty kit (Box 240)